Chad Young

677 Arrowood Court Los Altos, CA 94024 (650) 933-0747 chady64@outlook.com

SUMMARY

I am a game engineer who has always been fascinated with game engines like Game Maker Studio since I was young. I currently have experience with various game engines such as Unreal Engine and Unity, as well as programming languages like C++, Python, and Java. I also have experience working with teams and managing my own time, which is especially important in the career fields.

ATTRIBUTES

- Creative and innovative problem solver
- Strong writing skills, including grammar and style
- Ability to work quickly, with quality and attention to detail
- Outstanding team player

KNOWLEDGE AND SKILLS

- Excellent computer skills, including a strong aptitude for learning new programming languages and concepts.
- Experience in the following:
 - Unity
 - Unreal Engine
 - Godot
- Knowledgeable in the following programming languages.
 - o C++
 - Java
 - JavaScript
 - Python
 - o Lua
 - Unreal Blueprints
- Extensive knowledge of game design.
- Deep understanding of AAA games, the game industry, and game design.
- Strong knowledge of Unity and Unreal.
- Experienced in testing computer programs and video games.

EXPERIENCE

CTY Technologies

March 2024-Present

Founder and President

- Developed business plan, strategy and launched the company.
- Initiated business and marketing operations.
- Planned game studio operations for future in Game Developer Club.

University of Silicon Valley

Game Developer Club - Vice President

- Helped manage the club with the president and other leaders.
- Attended events in the club, including a game testing event.
- Working on a new game concept with club members.

The Museum of Art and Digital Entertainment, Oakland, CA

2019-2024

Volunteer Technical Assistant

- Repaired video game consoles, including problem diagnosis and repair of game units.
- Configured consoles and other game units for temporary museum exhibits.

PROJECTS

Return of the Tomb Raider

- Unreal Engine 5.4 Project.
- Worked on the Graveyard level found in the final game.
- Implemented the inventory system used in the game.

Oublivious

- Finished using the Godot game engine.
- Lead the development team and directed various concepts for the game.
- Programmed weapon mechanics, as well as player movement for the game.
- Worked with level designers on creating the level for the game.

Graybox

- Programmed using Unity 3
- Engineer as well as level designer for the project.
- Programmed character movement and power-ups for the game.
- Worked on creating levels for the game.

ISOBreaker

- Uses Visual Studio 2022 and QT 6.5
- QT C++ Program created from scratch with no prior experience.
- Supports multiple ISO formats, including standard, GameCube, and Xbox.
- Easy to use and a good alternative to other programs like ISOBuster.

EDUCATION

University of Silicon Valley, San Jose

September 2021-Present

Bachelor of Science, Game Engineering

GPA: 3.8

Foothill College, Los Altos Hills

September 2019 - December 2021

GPA: 3.8